Mega Evolution...
...is the endless potential a Pokémon possesses.
The disappearance of the legendary megalith that is the root of all this...
...turned out to be a mere sign of what was to come.
The Strongest Mega Evolution ~Act III~
All right!
Whoa!
What a great view!
It's called "Devon Corporation", Hari-san.
This company belongs to Daigo-san's father, you know!
I'll go on ahead.
Huh?
What? Non, non!
Tell me, don't you have this thing called "emotion"?
This is urgent.
You can come with me, but don't get in the way.
That guy really is too uptight.
This is footage from the sea 200 kilometers off Kanazumi City here.
While watching anime, make sure not to sit too close to the screen and that the room is well lit.
Let me show you our footage as well.
What's this advancing object?
I suspect it's the Continent Pokémon Groudon...
"Groudon"?
This is...?
It is a Pokémon said to have expanded the land.
So this little one is a Pokémon too.
Yeah.
I want you to see this.
Could this be...
...Primal Reversion?
Most likely.
"Primal Reversion"?
Play a board game via the Pocket Monsters XY data broadcast!
Press the d-button on your remote and try reaching the battles and the presents!!
According to books,
it's believed to restore the Pokémon's original appearance...
...and the great power it's supposed to have.
However,
if Groudon has appeared,
the other one...
"The other one"? Does that mean there's one more?
Manon! I told you not to get in the way.
I'm not in the way, I'm asking a question!
South from Rune City, deep in the ocean, we've captured a response from a huge living creature currently in motion.
Don't tell me that's Kyogre!
What?!
I knew it...
Has it come to destroy the world?
"Destroy"?
It's a myth.
A myth that's been passed on since olden times.
In the super-ancient world, Primal Groudon was said to have expanded the land,
while Primal Kyogre was said to have spread the sea.
Apparently, the two fought continuously for a certain kind of great energy.
Their fight shook heaven and earth violently, putting the world at risk of collapse.
There is also the belief that the energy the two were after is that legendary megalith.
That's right. The situation is grave.
If the energy we've detected off the coast of Kanazumi City really does indicate the appearance of the legendary megalith...
Groudon on the sea...
Kyogre deep within the sea...
If we estimate the direction in which they're advancing....
They all overlap.
So it's all according to the myth...
If that happens, the world will...
No way...
Director, I will head to the site.
Yeah. I'll count on you.
I'll go too. Let me prepare a means of transport.
Yeah, please do.
Uhm...
Daigo-san!
Isn't this dangerous?
We're only going to check the situation from the sky.
I'll go on ahead.
Yeah.
Uh, Alan!
What about your shoulder?
Doesn't it hurt any more?
No, it's fine.
There's no time to dawdle around. I'll go on ahead.
I'm not going.
I see.
Alan, you musn't go either!
I'm scared...
So much...
Alan, aren't you scared?
Rayquaza was really angry back then...
Rayquaza alone was that strong...
...and now there's two Pokémon that want to wreck the world!
Alan...
This time you won't get away with just an injury...
This is a promise.
A promise?
A promise to the director.
I have to gain power...
...and become strong.
I have to become the strongest...
But to become the strongest,
how far will you have to go?
Do you have to fight against the world's destruction?
What do you know about it?
But I...
...don't want...
anything...
...to happen to you...
Go back to Kalos.
Uh, Alan...!
Wait, Alan!
Are you really okay with leaving her behind?
She's just a burden.
I don't quite believe you.
Oops, sorry.
And here I thought it was your way of being kind.
As one would expect, it's hot.
The temperature of the air outside is over 60 degrees Celsius and still rising.
Ugh, it's hot.
Hari-san, fire an Ice Beam.
Right.
In a short time, we'll reach our destination, point zero.
Groudon detected.
Groudon has suddenly appeared.
Just where is it heading?
It is dangerous here. Please leave immediately.
Is that Groudon?
What's that?
We have a high energy response from point zero off Kanazumi.
What?
The pattern matches with that of the megalith.
It really is that megalith...
Can you two hear me?
Director?
Fleur-de-lis-san?
We've detected the energy as well.
Though we've had no response from it as a single entity yet.
We don't know what will happen from now on.
Take good care of yourself when proceeding with the investigation.
We will.
I know.
Something is moving through the sea.
It will reach the surface before long.
Kyogre...
What? What?
What's going on?
No way!
I-Is that...
...Kyogre?
Coming up next:
Clash! Legend VS Legend!!
This program is brought to you by these sponsors.
What is the Houen region's fate!?
Does Groudon and Kyogre's appearance mean...
...the myth passed down here in the Houen region will become reality now?
The expansion rate of the energy above the sea has increased even more.
As a result, the crystallographic density is increasing faster and faster. It's beginning to solidify.
It's the megalith, as expected.
Yeah.
Can you hear me, Alan?
This message is for you only.
The vanished megalith will probably crystallize here.
We'll be heading there as well. Until then, please protect the megalith from those two.
Being in the hands of humans is what gives that thing meaning.
Understood.
Alan, what are you up to?!
We'll stop those two!
Go, Lizardon!
Lizardon,
mega evolve!
Mega Lizardon?
Are you telling me Lizardon can protect the megalith from those two all by itself?
I can't just watch!
Geez, I can't believe you...
We'll take on Kyogre.
Metagross, mega evolve!
Flamethrower!
Flash Cannon!
Dragon Claw!
Meteor Mash!
Steel Wing!
Lizardon!
Alan!
Huh? Alan?
Alan, stop! Stop it!
Lizardon!
Return, Lizardon!
Alan!
Open! Open, open!
Descend!
Understood!
All right!
What?
What is it?
The rear hatch!
Manon?!
Alan!
Alan, wake up!
Wake up!
Manon!
No!
Metagross, thank you!
Well done, Metagross.
Keep protecting the two of them!
I've got to hand it to you, Hari-san!
I wonder if he'll be all right here.
That's...
It has finally regenerated.
What's this?
Could it be...?
Mega...
...Rayquaza?
I can't believe its power...
Alan!
Manon?
Rayquaza?!
What's that?
The response from the megalith has vanished!
What?!
The megalith has disappeared...
It's a success.
Huh?
We've analyzed the components we gathered from the megalith last time and created a system that blocks its energy radiation.
Daigo-san, the megalith will remain with me for a while.
With you?
Yes, I will take it to Kalos.
I wonder what that was about.
Manon.
Alan...
Were you scared?
Yeah...
But, uhm...
I was really worried, so...
Thank you.
The brutal Pokémon that appeared off Kanazumi City have disappeared, restoring calm to the neighboring towns.
Champion Daigo made an effort to put the situation under control.
Could it be...?
Alan?
What?! He went back?
He said that you'd only be in danger if you were by his side.
I'll go back too!
Manon-kun!
Yes?
If you want...
I'll give you a ride.
Really?
We've gained more Mega Evolution energy from this megalith than expected.
The project that will attain the peace I aim for moves onto the next stage.
It's thanks to you, Alan.
Thank you very much.
You've done a good job.
Rest for a bit.
No.
Neither me nor Lizardon are anywhere near being the strongest.
I want to become strong!
Are you all right?
Flamethrower!
Dragon Claw!
The events that transpired in Houen will lead to a change in the Kalos region's future.
This change will be great tidings of joy to humanity and Pokémon alike.
It won't be long before humanity will get to hear it.